NEN
[narrator] Nen abilities fall into
the following six distinct categories:
Enhancers are able
to strengthen and reinforce
the natural properties
of any object they encounter.
Transmuters can manipulate and change
the quality of aura at will.
Similar to Transmuters,
Conjurers have the ability
to materialize an object out of aura.
Emitters can propel their aura,
shooting or projecting it forward.
Manipulators can use their aura
to control objects or living things.
Specialists possess rare abilities
which do not fit
within the other five categories.
One must determine
which category their aura falls into.
This is the first step
to becoming a skilled Nen user.
[theme song playing]
The auction, as you all know,
will begin in one month.
Before that time,
find one item from the list provided
and then bring it safely back here.
[surprised gasp]
THE EYEBALLS OF A KURTA
[breathes heavily]
[man on the screen] If you’re successful,
you’ll be hired
and begin your training
in security and acquisitions.
[Kurapika] In all likelihood,
the man we saw was not the actual client,
thus, illustrating the distance
between the client and myself.
It’s critical that I get
as close to them as possible,
until they eventually let their guard down
and share their secrets.
I will pass this test.
First, I must ingratiate myself
and win their trust.
NEN x USERS x UNITE
[man] Hey… It won’t open.
Huh?
[man on the screen]
I forgot to mention one thing.
The minimum requirement
for the position is strength.
Enough strength
to get out of this mansion
with your lives.
[intense music playing]
DOWSING CHAIN:
THE GUIDING RING FINGER CHAIN
[gunshots]
[groaning in pain]
[man]
He used a chain to stop the bullets!
Impressive.
-[clatter]
-[chain rattles]
[grunting]
[Kurapika] Three with guns.
Six with swords.
Two more with swords above.
Good job concealing your presence, guys.
But unfortunately for you,
you’re too weak! [grunts]
As a matter of fact,
I don’t even need to use my Nen!
[gasps]
So that’s what’s going on.
I get it now.
It’s him.
[all gasp]
[gasps]
-Call them off right now.
-[grunts]
I’ll count to three.
One, two…
Okay, okay!
Whatever you say.
-[gasps]
-Wait. What’s going on?
They were made of Nen.
I knew as soon as I punched one of ‘em.
They’re just masses of aura
shaped like men. They’re weak.
I didn’t realize it was his Nen.
Impressive. How'd you know?
You were careful to stand next to
the others for camouflage.
But when I watched you from above,
it was clear.
Every one of us was under attack,
except you.
Oh?
[Kurapika] I realized something was wrong
when two of them appeared
on the second floor.
After I jumped over to the chandelier
and out of their reach,
they just stood there,
continuing to swing their swords,
in a futile attempt to reach me.
I have to assume
they received a basic order
-to attack whichever enemy was nearest.
-[grunts]
The instructions the assailants had
were simple,
so their attacks were as well.
However, it would take
an incredibly skilled Nen user
to control eleven
human-sized aura simultaneously.
And it stands to reason
that this Nen user would
most likely be an Emitter.
And given the size of the aura involved,
he would have to be
within a few meters of the assailants.
Which meant that the Nen user…
was someone inside this very room.
[whistles]
Well, yeah, you nailed it.
My name is Shachmono Tocino.
As you might’ve guessed, I'm a Hunter.
Of course, I’m also an employee here,
which means I’m basically your senior.
Now that’s cleared up,
think you could put away your knife?
[sighs]
Based on the chains,
I think it’s fairly safe to assume
that you’re a Manipulator, aren’t you?
Well, I sure hope you won’t hold a grudge.
See, I was only following the orders
the boss gave me.
“Test the applicants
by attempting to kill them.”
But I honestly never expected
to be exposed so quickly!
Well, I’m willing to bet
that the four of you together
should be able to escape the mansion.
So best of luck.
‘Four of you”?
That makes it sound like
there’s another one in the room.
[chuckles]
I imagine that was meant to be
some sort of diversion,
but it was the wrong call.
Before we all succumb to paranoia,
I shall determine if there are
any other infiltrators among us.
[scoffs]
[grunts]
[all gasp]
There you are.
You are the infiltrator.
[chain rattles]
That’s ridiculous!
What grounds are you basing that on?
Just ‘cause your chain started swinging?
[short woman] It’s called dowsing.
Huh? And what’s that supposed to mean?
[short woman]
Dowsing was originally a technique
for locating water or other metals
hidden beneath the ground.
But it was also used in divination.
I’ve even heard of the technique
being employed as a kind of lie detector.
Okay, maybe so,
but that still isn’t concrete proof
that I’m the infiltrator!
It doesn’t prove anything!
Well, in any case, he’s probably right.
Your heart.
I noticed it began to pound
as soon as he pointed his finger at you.
Of course, if you were innocent…
your heart rate would have increased
much more gradually
due to the stress
of being wrongly accused.
But your heartbeat
sped up almost immediately
before gradually slowing
back down again.
[light giggle]
The typical melody of a liar,
no doubt about it.
-That’s true for both of you.
-Hm?
[cracking knuckles]
Well, I’m convinced.
Both of them are saying it’s you.
That’s two accusations out of five.
Hold on! Wait a second!
That doesn’t necessarily make it true!
Maybe three out of five of us
are the applicants
and those two are the infiltrators!
[Kurapika] Not so.
He is not one of the infiltrators.
Excuse me, but…
I think you mean ‘she’, not ‘he’.
I can vouch for you, too.
My point is that
none of us can really trust either of you!
How do we know
you’re not working together, huh?
[scoffs]
[short woman] Hmm…
[scoffs] Anyway, all we’re doing
is wasting time.
We can stand around here all you like,
but it isn’t going to get us anywhere.
[scoffs]
That’s it, then.
I’ll have to settle this myself.
“My hand makes a punch
and whatever I hit
will burst in flames
-a bunch.”
-Huh?
[all gasp]
This is my power.
The Wandering Haiku Poet!
Well, dammit.
It didn’t burn well.
Guess it was a dud.
Huh?
That was a haiku, if you couldn’t tell,
the prized literary art of my homeland.
Whatever I compose
becomes real.
[all] Huh?
So, there’s your explanation.
Back to the subject at hand.
[gasps]
“If you’re a liar
your painful death will be swift
in trial by fire.”
In other words…
anyone who lies to me will burn in hell.
[gulps]
My question is…
are you an infiltrator?
No, I’m not.
What about you?
[short woman] I am not.
And as for you?
Me neither.
And are you an infiltrator?
Yeah. I sure am.
[grunts]
[poet] I’ll advise you to think carefully
before you answer.
Are you one of the infiltrators?
Well? I’m waiting for an answer!
[intense music plays]
[heavy sigh]
My answer’s "Yes, I am."
[grunts] That was impressive.
I’ll reward you with some information.
My name is Squala.
And while I may not have
an official license,
I’m a Hunter whose skills
fall into the Manipulator class. Hmm.
I’ve used those abilities
to instruct something
to follow a certain order.
It’s true you managed to unmask me,
but that doesn’t mean you’ll be able
to escape this mansion alive.
[woman] What’s the ‘something’
and what was the order?
[scoffs]
That wouldn’t be much of a test,
if I just told you, now would it?
Imbecile.
[scoffs]
I’m not gonna talk even if you torture me.
Huh?
[grunts nervously]
[electricity buzzes]
[high-pitched voice echoing] Wow!
This is my Nen ability…
Instant Lover.
I am also a Manipulator.
I can kiss absolutely anyone
and make them my slave.
[smitten panting]
M-- M-- Mistress!
[woman] Take that, and that, and that,
and that, and that!
[Squala] [ecstatic cry] More!
Oh, please! Step on me more!
[woman] Now, answer my question!
What did you use Nen on
and what was your command?
Say it! C’mon!
If you don’t answer me, I’ll stop!
[Squala] [cries out]
Don't stop! I’ll talk!
Yes! I’m just a lowly dog trainer!
[Kurapika] Such a…
[poet] …fearsome power…
[Squala] I’ll tell you everything!
I used my Nen on the dogs
that run around this mansion!
For example…
the Maltese were told
to nip at a target’s feet
to try and slow them down.
That’s when the Saint Bernard comes in!
It’s supposed to use its large body
to smother them!
And at the exact same time,
the Dobermans will rush in
and finish off the target for good!
If the target still escapes,
the bulldogs will--
-[cries out in pain]
-[woman] That's enough!
Release the Nen you used on the dogs!
[Squala] Right away!
[growling]
So, the dog trainer
has been reduced down to a loyal pet, huh?
Oh, don’t say that.
The only reason I did it
was to make him talk.
If I wanted a man as a pet,
I could do a whole lot better than him.
That reminds me,
I don’t think I ever caught your name.
Mine is Basho.
And as you saw just a few minutes ago,
I’m a Conjurer.
My name is Baise.
I’m Melody.
It seems like you can hear heartbeats.
What category is that?
Oh, you’ll find out soon enough, I’m sure.
Oh, I see. Playing coy then, are we?
What about you?
Hmm. I’d like to know your name
if you don’t mind.
Would you please tell us?
I will not.
We don’t yet know
if we will be working together.
Yes, he has a point.
We cleared the first stage
by escaping the mansion,
but the real test has only just begun.
You're right, we need to locate
one of the designated items
from the list we received,
or we can’t get the job.
[Basho] If we’re all after the same gig,
we’re bound to run into each other again.
[tall man]
What’s your opinion of this group?
[Tocino]
This one in particular looks promising.
At least,
more than him.
[scoffs] It will be a while
before I require him,
so just put him away for the time being.
I trust you can handle that, Squala.
Y-- Yes, sir.
[Kurapika] If I find one of the objects
and earn the contract,
I will have passage
to the Yorknew City auction.
Yes. I will attend!
After all,
the Phantom Troupe will undoubtedly
be in attendance as well.
The band of thieves
that slaughtered my fellow Kurta.
When we’re overcome with emotion,
our eyes burn a deep scarlet.
They were willing to kill
in order to obtain those eyes,
considered one of the world’s
seven most beautiful colors.
I will never forgive that act.
I will track them down…
and I will destroy them!
[bird screeching]
[keyboard keys clacking]
[Milluki] Hm. So, this is Greed Island.
It’s starting to look like
the memory card Kil found
might actually be the real deal.
I figured that you could analyze the data
and reverse engineer the game itself,
couldn’t you?
You bet I can.
I’ll strip down the code
and clear the entire game.
I’ll put an end to the legend
and win 50 billion Jenny in the process.
Oh, right.
This was a trade.
I'm gonna have to tell Kil the URL
for the Hunter-only website.
If I don’t hold up my end of the bargain,
that little brat might start talking
about breaking my precious figures again.
[waves crashing]
[Gon] That’s it. Right over there, Killua!
Yeah. We’re almost there. Yorknew.
Can you believe we’re gonna
get to see Kurapika and Leorio again?
I can hardly wait!
You’re kinda jumping the gun.
We’ve still got two weeks
before we’re supposed to meet up.
Oh, right.
It’s been six months
since we saw them last
and I’m getting excited!
And six months ago,
I never would have dreamed
we’d come to Yorknew City.
Not for this, anyway.
[Leorio] Till next time…
[Kurapika] Yes. That will be…
[all] September 1st, in Yorknew City!
[Killua] The auction starts
on September 1st,
so we need to gather as much info
on Greed Island
as possible before then.
Mm-hmm. And if we’re lucky,
we might even find out
some more information about Ging.
Well, he did leave you a memory card,
along with that recorded message.
There’s gotta be a connection.
But no matter what,
once my brother sends that URL to us,
we can check it out, right?
Mm-hmm.
[chuckles softly]
-[bird screeching]
-[gasps]
[bird screeching]
This is it, Gon.
My brother sent the URL.
Wow, that's awesome! Let’s get started!
Yeah!
[narrator] Driven by their various goals,
Gon and Killua
prepare for September 1st.
With the Yorknew City Auction
mere weeks away,
there’s no telling what they’ll discover
when it begins.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon…
-[Killua] …and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Melody!
She's a Music Hunter!
She reads your state of mind
by your heartbeat.
So, her senses must be amazing!
Hey, Killua, you ate my chocolate?
-Nah.
-Not convinced.
[Gon] Next time:
"Gathering x Of x Heroes"!
Killua! Did you know
I could tell fortunes?
[Killua] Really?
[Gon] Everybody who watched
Hunter x Hunter today is really happy!